<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-16T23:04:28-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Darron Froese]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I want in a Canadian Virtual Private Server provider.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/02/06/what-i-want-in-a-canadian-virtual-private-server-provider-/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/02/06/what-i-want-in-a-canadian-virtual-private-server-provider-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m trying to find a decent Canadian VPS provider that I can use for some of my customers.</p>
<p>Yes - I know that having your data in Canada is not really any safer than having it hosted in the USA, but I can&#8217;t fully convince some of my client&#8217;s legal departments.</p>
<p>I need:</p>
<p>1. The ability to start up additional instances without calling somebody or filling out a form so that they will &#8220;get back to me&#8221;. Ideally there would be an <a href="http://docs.rackspace.com/servers/api/v2/cs-gettingstarted/content/overview.html">api</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/mobile/">iPhone app</a> or <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/">web interface</a> where I can do just that - just like I already do with <a href="http://aws.amazon.com">Amazon Web Services</a> and <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/">Rackspace Cloud</a>.</p>
<p>2. Ubuntu LTS is required - CentOS or Windows only need not apply.</p>
<p>
<p>3.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rackspace.com/knowledge_center/article/rackspace-cloud-backup-overview">Onsite backups at reasonable prices</a>. I will take care of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.strongspace.com">offsite snapshots</a>&nbsp;- likely in the USA as I can&#8217;t find reasonable storage costs for 200+GB in Canada.</p>
<p>4. Reliability - I am not interested in the lowest price - I will pay more if the servers are stable.</p>
<p>5. No yearly contracts.</p>
</p>
<p>I want:</p>
<p>1. Ability to scale up those instances dynamically - <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/knowledge_center/article/managing-your-server-6-resizing-your-server">just like I can currently do</a> with Rackspace Cloud.</p>
<p>2. Multiple locations in Canada would be nice.</p>
<p>3. Would be awesome if they worked with <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">Chef</a> or had a <a href="https://github.com/opscode/knife-rackspace">knife</a> <a href="https://github.com/opscode/knife-ec2">plugin</a> - but not a deal breaker - I can always just <a href="http://docs.opscode.com/knife_bootstrap.html">knife bootstrap</a>&nbsp;them.</p>
<p>4. Pay by the hour resources - but will pay by the month / quarter if needed.</p>
<p>Is this too much to ask?</p>
<p>Anybody know of a company with Canadian server hardware that fits the bill?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More falsehoods programmers believe about time; "wisdom of the crowd" edition: @NoahSussman: Infinite Undo]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/01/03/more-falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-time-wisdom-of-the-crowd-edition-noahsussman-infinite-undo/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/01/03/more-falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-time-wisdom-of-the-crowd-edition-noahsussman-infinite-undo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><strong>A great many of the false assumptions listed were my own.</strong>  Especially “time stamps are always in seconds since epoch” and “the duration of a system clock minute is always pretty close to the duration of a wall clock minute.”  Whoa did I ever live to regret my ignorance in those two cases!  But hey, apparently I’m not the only one who has run into (or inadvertently caused) such issues.  A lot of people responded and shared similar experiences.</blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://infiniteundo.com/post/25509354022/more-falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-time-wisdom">infiniteundo.com</a></div>
    <p>Good stuff - working with time is always lots of fun.</p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A little Chef advice is needed - how to move forward. #opschef]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/29/a-little-chef-advice-is-needed-how-to-move-forward-opschef/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/29/a-little-chef-advice-is-needed-how-to-move-forward-opschef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chef workflow question&#8230;</p>
<p>Looking for a little advice here on how to move forward with some Chef built infrastructure.</p>
<p>I started going through my chef repo this Christmas - and some ugly little platform version hacks started appearing - so I got to thinking about how better to structure things - and here I am.</p>
<p>We have about 20 Rackspace Cloud Ubuntu 10.0.4 boxes running various parts of <a href="http://www.nonfiction.ca/">nonfiction&#8217;s</a> web infrastructure - they&#8217;re working great and are current with all patches, etc. I&#8217;m not likely to &#8220;dist-upgrade&#8221; them - but they&#8217;re going to be alive for a few years at least.</p>
<p>I built them with my first Chef recipes and am now wanting to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Start deploying Ubuntu 12.0.4 boxes on Rackspace&#8217;s new OpenStack architecture.</li>
<li>Not break my existing infrastructure - they work great - even though the cookbooks are a little raw in places.</li>
<li>Update my chef cookbooks and use more community cookbooks with <a href="http://berkshelf.com">Berkshelf</a>, <a href="http://vagrantup.com">Vagrant</a>, Jenkins, etc.</li>
<li>Stop using roles - which were used extensively before.</li>
</ol>
<p>These boxes are built and all installed packages and software are managed with Chef - but much of the data on them isn&#8217;t managed in Chef - clients upload their own files, etc. Between DNS that I don&#8217;t manage 100% and that customer data, it&#8217;s not super simple to just &#8220;redeploy&#8221; and rebuild everything.</p>
<p>So my plan is to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create an environment called &#8220;lucid&#8221;.</li>
<li>Freeze all the current cookbook versions and assign them to that environment.</li>
<li>Create a new environment called &#8220;precise&#8221;</li>
<li>Deploy new boxes using that environment.</li>
<li>Fork my own chef repo and rebuild / test with Berkshelf, Vagrant, Jenkins, etc.</li>
<li>If a Lucid box can be discarded and rebuilt with Precise - I&#8217;ll do it - but likely not all of them.</li>
</ol>
<p>What do other people do when they&#8217;re updating their infrastructure like this? New chef repo? Keep it all in one? Any tips? I&#8217;ve been looking through all sorts of links online and haven&#8217;t seen much of that sort of discussion.</p>
<p>Reading through <a href="http://jtimberman.housepub.org/blog/2012/11/19/chef-repository-berkshelf-conversion/">this article</a> it looks like he converted his chef-repo and just kept moving - that sort of scares me a little bit - but I guess is an option.</p>
<p>Any tips / links would be appreciated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milk prices may double in the New Year - Why does this still happen?]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/22/milk-prices-may-double-in-the-new-year-why-does-this-still-happen-/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/22/milk-prices-may-double-in-the-new-year-why-does-this-still-happen-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>It works like this: In order to keep <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2012/11/27/news/economy/farming/index.html?iid=EL">dairy farmers</a> in businesses, the government agrees to buy milk and other products if the price gets too low. The current <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2012/12/04/news/economy/farm-subsidies/index.html?iid=EL">agriculture bill</a> has a formula that  means the government steps in if the price of milk were to drop by roughly half from its current national average of about $3.65 a gallon.
                       
                   </p>    
                   <p>
                        Problem is, the current bill expired last summer, and Congress had been unable to agree on a new one. Several protections for farmers have already expired, and several more are set to do so over the next few months. One of them is the dairy subsidy, which expires January 1.
                       
                   </p>    
                   <p>
                        But instead of leaving farmers entirely out in the cold, the law states that if a new bill isn&#8217;t passed or the current one extended, the formula for calculating the price the government pays for dairy products reverts back to a 1949 statute. Under that formula, the government would be forced to buy milk at twice today&#8217;s price &#8211; driving up the cost for everyone.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2012/12/21/news/economy/milk-prices/index.html?hpt=hp_t1">money.cnn.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's cool when Clinton proposes it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/21/it-s-cool-when-clinton-proposes-it-/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/21/it-s-cool-when-clinton-proposes-it-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>&#8220;These districts are bringing school nurses and counselors together to respond to warning signs like depression or bullying,&#8221; Clinton said. &#8220;They are improving classroom security and expanding after-school and mentoring programs.&#8221;</p><p>Clinton also unveiled the $60-million fifth round of funding for &#8220;COPS in School,&#8221; a Justice Department program that helps pay the costs of placing police officers in schools to help make them safer for students and teachers. The money will be used to provide 452 officers in schools in more than 220 communities.</p><p>&#8220;Already, it has placed 2,200 officers in more than 1,000 communities across our nation, where they are heightening school safety as well as coaching sports and acting as mentors and mediators for kids in need,&#8221; Clinton said.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2000/apr/16/news/mn-20323">articles.latimes.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Secret History of Guns - Adam Winkler - The Atlantic]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/20/the-secret-history-of-guns-adam-winkler-the-atlantic/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/20/the-secret-history-of-guns-adam-winkler-the-atlantic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote">I<span style="">ndisputably, for much </span>of American history, gun-control measures, like many other laws, were used to oppress African Americans. The South had long prohibited blacks, both slave and free, from owning guns. In the North, however, at the end of the Civil War, the Union army allowed soldiers of any color to take home their rifles. Even blacks who hadn’t served could buy guns in the North, amid the glut of firearms produced for the war. President Lincoln had promised a “new birth of freedom,” but many blacks knew that white Southerners were not going to go along easily with such a vision. As one freedman in Louisiana recalled, “I would say to every colored soldier, ‘Bring your gun home.’”</blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2011/09/the-secret-history-of-guns/308608/?single_page=true">theatlantic.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas School District Allows Teachers to Carry Guns in Classrooms]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/texas-school-district-allows-teachers-to-carry-guns-in-classrooms/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/texas-school-district-allows-teachers-to-carry-guns-in-classrooms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p><span style="font-size: medium;">There&#8217;s a lot of talk about how to deal with incidents like the Sandy Hook Elementary shooting in Newtown Connecticut, and one being floated by conservatives is the idea of arming school teachers and administrators.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a far out idea.&nbsp; The Harrold ISD in North Texas has allowed teachers to carry guns in the classroom since 2008, according to principal David Thweatt.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">&nbsp; &#8220;If you are unarmed, these people are going into those areas where they know people will not be able to resist,&#8221; Thweatt told 1200 WOAI news.</span></p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://radio.woai.com/cc-common/mainheadlines3.html?feed=119078&amp;article=10646958">radio.woai.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off duty security guard stops douchebag.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/off-duty-security-guard-stops-douchebag-/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/off-duty-security-guard-stops-douchebag-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p><span style="font-size: medium;">&nbsp; Antu says the gunman never made it into the theater itself, thanks largely to the heroic work of the off duty deputy.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">&nbsp; &#8220;She did what she felt she had to do,&#8221; Antu said.&nbsp; &#8220;I feel that she saved a lot of lives by taking the action she had to take.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://radio.woai.com/cc-common/mainheadlines3.html?feed=119078&amp;article=10644119#ixzz2FP2SiZCm">radio.woai.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man says he had shooter in his sights, but chose safety over firing]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/man-says-he-had-shooter-in-his-sights-but-chose-safety-over-firing/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/man-says-he-had-shooter-in-his-sights-but-chose-safety-over-firing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote">Meli earlier told a KGW reporter that he heard three gunshots, and then positioned himself behind a pillar in the mall. Meli said he saw the gunman working on his rifle, pulling a charging handle and hitting the side of the weapon. &nbsp;<p>Meli said he then pulled out his Glock 22 pistol and aimed it at the suspect. But when he saw someone move behind Roberts, Meli decided against firing, concerned he might hit an innocent person. </p><p>Meli also told KGW that Roberts appeared to spot him and that afterward, Meli heard only one more shot, and suspects it was the one Roberts used to kill himself.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.oregonlive.com/clackamascounty/index.ssf/2012/12/security_guard_said_he_had_rob.html">oregonlive.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auditing Shooting Rampage Statistics - Daily Anarchist]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/auditing-shooting-rampage-statistics-daily-anarchist/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/18/auditing-shooting-rampage-statistics-daily-anarchist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p><strong>The average number of people killed in mass shootings when stopped by police is 14.29</strong></p>
<p><strong>The average number of people killed in a mass shooting when stopped by a civilian is&nbsp;2.33</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://dailyanarchist.com/2012/07/31/auditing-shooting-rampage-statistics/">dailyanarchist.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Technologies: We are a world of gadgeteers. - Node is so cool.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/11/variable-technologies-we-are-a-world-of-gadgeteers-node-is-so-cool-/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/12/11/variable-technologies-we-are-a-world-of-gadgeteers-node-is-so-cool-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      [[posterous-content:mnlHiJJyrgAcIJbGbFdi]]<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.variabletech.com/products/">variabletech.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health-care battle heats up]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/08/20/health-care-battle-heats-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/08/20/health-care-battle-heats-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>&#8220;She may have terminal cancer, but she still goes for walks and even plays a little golf,&#8221; Day said. &#8220;Then she injured her knee, and all she wants to do is enjoy the quality of life she has remaining. She wants to go for her walks.</p><p>&#8220;But the government says, &#8216;No, you have to wait.&#8217; They handed an 18-month sentence to a woman who may have only 18 months, or less, to live.&#8221;</p><p>Krahn is one of four patients named in Day&#8217;s lawsuit, which argues the constitutional right to &#8220;life, liberty and security of the person&#8221; means they should be allowed to spend their own money on their own health care when that care is denied by the government.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.theprovince.com/health/Health+care+battle+heats/7112772/story.html">theprovince.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 | Homeboy Industries Reboots The Lives Of Tattooed Former Gangbangers, And Even One CEO | Co.Exist: World changing ideas and innovation]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/07/16/8-homeboy-industries-reboots-the-lives-of-tattooed-former-gangbangers-and-even-one-ceo-co-exist-world-changing-ideas-and-innovation/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/07/16/8-homeboy-industries-reboots-the-lives-of-tattooed-former-gangbangers-and-even-one-ceo-co-exist-world-changing-ideas-and-innovation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_short_quote">From Boyle’s perspective, Homeboy was primarily in the business of hiring people: &#8220;We don’t hire homies to bake bread. We bake bread to hire homies.</blockquote><div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.fastcoexist.com/1679680/homeboy-industries-reboots-the-lives-of-tattooed-former-gangbangers-and-even-one-ceo#8">fastcoexist.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeff Loflin was talking about Sidemount Diving at The Dive Shop today]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/07/08/jeff-loflin-was-talking-about-sidemount-diving-at-the-dive-shop-today/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/07/08/jeff-loflin-was-talking-about-sidemount-diving-at-the-dive-shop-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went to a presentation at <a href="http://www.diveshopscuba.com/" title="The Dive Shop Calgary">The Dive Shop</a> by visiting instructor <a href="http://www.jeffloflin.com/" title="Jeff Loflin | Technical, Sidemount, and Cave Dive Training">Jeff Loflin</a> on Cave diving and the path to Full Cave (and beyond) last night.</p>
<p>It was interesting enough to me, so I bought his <a href="http://www.sidemountvideo.com/" title="Sidemount Video">new sidemount training video</a> and watched it last night waiting for a chance to try out a sidemount rig today.</p>
<p>Today Jeff gave another 1.5 hour presentation on the changes he&#8217;s seen to sidemount over the last 6 years, he traced its evolution from Europe a few decades ago, to where it is today - the <strong>new big thing</strong>&trade;.</p>
<p>After the talk, a bunch of us got a chance to try out the Hollis sidemount gear - I tried out the <a href="http://www.hollisgear.com/prodview.asp?id=121" title="Hollis Gear: SMS 100">Hollis SMS 100</a> - the &#8220;technical&#8221; level sidemount rig.</p>
<h2>What I liked and thought was interesting:</h2>
<ul>
<li>2 completely independent life-support systems.</li>
<li>12 lbs - which means I don&#8217;t need any additional weight in warm water diving.</li>
<li>Full visibility of all life-support failure points.</li>
<li>Visibility of both of the pressure gauges - right in front of my face at all times. No reaching way down to unclip, plus move bottles, and bring up as high as possible.</li>
<li>Streamlining would help in restrictions and tighter wreck situations.</li>
<li>Valve drills for first two tanks would be very easy - ludicrously easy.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re travelling you don&#8217;t need to bring your tanks and manifolds if you want to do more advanced diving - just use whatever tanks are available - would potentially be very handy.</li>
<li>Easy on/off of tanks in the water - no need to move around massive tanks in pairs.</li>
<li>A very versatile BC with tons of options and ways to set it up. One tank. Two tanks. Sidemount. Back mount.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What I didn&#8217;t totally like (mostly about sidemount, less about the Hollis rig itself):</h2>
<ul>
<li>2 completely independent life-support systems - I&#8217;m still partial to having my primary back gas manifolded at this time.</li>
<li>Having to swap regulators every 500 psi - just another thing to do.</li>
<li>Not being able to instinctively donate the reg that&#8217;s in my mouth to an out-of-air diver - if I&#8217;m breathing from the left tank, then I need to donate the long hose on my right. Another thing to think about in a possible emergency.</li>
<li>There&#8217;s a lot of pieces that come in front of my chest - I&#8217;m used to this from the tech diving gear, but it seemed much more tangled up.</li>
<li>Seems way less stable than my twinset - way more little pieces and flexing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some of my concerns are likely because they&#8217;re new and different to what I&#8217;m used to - not sure if they&#8217;re all legit at this point without dropping another $1k and trying it out for a while. (Not this year.)</p>
<ul>
</ul>
<p>Am I gonna switch over? Not likely at this point - unless I:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sold my <a href="http://www.revo-rebreathers.com/">rEvo</a> and wanted to do more Open Circuit. (Ummmmm - nope.)</li>
<li>Was doing really tight caves and restriction penetrations. (Yeah - that&#8217;s still terrifying for me.)</li>
</ol>
<p>But it was interesting to see - and food for thought at least.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canada's election laws changing to reflect Twitter reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/14/canada-s-election-laws-changing-to-reflect-twitter-reality/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/14/canada-s-election-laws-changing-to-reflect-twitter-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>The Harper government will repeal the ban on communicating election results while polls are still open, bringing the law into harmony with the realities of today&#8217;s instant communications.</p><p></p><p>The election night blackout was adopted in 1938, to prevent western voters from knowing the results of the election in the east when they cast their ballots.</p><p></p><p>Minister of State for Democratic Reform Tim Uppal announced via Twitter Friday that the antiquated law will been repealed in time for the next election.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.canada.com/technology/Canada+election+laws+changing+reflect+Twitter+reality/5991515/story.html?cid=dlvr.it">canada.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to gun owners: We made a mistake. Fix it for us or go to prison | Canadian gun laws are messed up.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/12/government-to-gun-owners-we-made-a-mistake-fix-it-for-us-or-go-to-prison-canadian-gun-laws-are-messed-up-/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/12/government-to-gun-owners-we-made-a-mistake-fix-it-for-us-or-go-to-prison-canadian-gun-laws-are-messed-up-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>With the G22 rifle, the RCMP has at least a flimsy excuse for the reclassification— it says because the rifle can be easily shortened by removing the back end, it’s too easily concealable to be a non-restricted rifle (the blame still lies with the government for making the mistake in the first place, but at least that’s something). The decision to ban the AP-80, however, has no logic behind it at all. The RCMP claims that it was “incorrectly registered” as non-restricted because the AP-80 is a “variant of the design of the firearm commonly known as the AK-47 rifle” — a Soviet-designed military combat rifle.</p>
<p>Except … it isn’t. At all. The AP-80 fires an entirely different (and much weaker) kind of ammunition, using a different internal mechanism and is built from completely different materials and components (precisely zero of the parts of the AP-80 and AK-47 are compatible or interchangeable). The only thing the AP-80 has in common with the AK-47 is its silhouette — when the AP-80 was designed, the manufacturer decided to make it look like the famous AK-47, for purely marketing reasons. As a rifle, the AP-80 is a completely unremarkable low-caliber plinker. Only by making it look like a famous military rifle could the company hope to sell many copies, so that’s what they did. The RCMP is banning the AP-80 because it looks scary.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://fullcomment.nationalpost.com/2012/01/10/government-to-gun-owners-we-made-a-mistake-fix-it-for-us-or-go-to-prison/">fullcomment.nationalpost.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Need to combine a bunch of PDF files in pure ruby?]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/11/need-to-combine-a-bunch-of-pdf-files-in-pure-ruby-/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/01/11/need-to-combine-a-bunch-of-pdf-files-in-pure-ruby-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Found a great set of gems:</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/paulschreiber/pdf-merger">PDF Merger</a>&nbsp;(also requires<span style=""> </span><a href="http://rjb.rubyforge.org/">RJB</a>, and <a href="http://itextpdf.com/download.php">iText</a>)</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve got your JRE installed and iText installed - install the gems:</p>
<p>gem install pdf-merger<br /> gem install rjb</p>
<p>Then this code is as simple as it gets:</p>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/1596012.js?file=gistfile1.rb"></script>
<p>That&#8217;s it - works well on OS X - haven&#8217;t tried it elsewhere yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sysadvent: Day 9 - Data in the Shell | Some great tools here.]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/25/sysadvent-day-9-data-in-the-shell-some-great-tools-here-/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/25/sysadvent-day-9-data-in-the-shell-some-great-tools-here-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote"><p>The shell is where I live most days, and the shell has pipes. Pipes simply transmit plain text, and many pieces of data I deal with are structured data where staples like grep and sed are not the best.</p><p>Fortunately, there are lots of tools available to help you deal with these structured formats.</p></blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://sysadvent.blogspot.com/2011/12/day-9-data-in-shell.html?m=1">sysadvent.blogspot.com</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[McDonald’s withdrawal from Bolivia: capitalism in action | Institute of Economic Affairs]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/20/mcdonald-s-withdrawal-from-bolivia-capitalism-in-action-institute-of-economic-affairs/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/20/mcdonald-s-withdrawal-from-bolivia-capitalism-in-action-institute-of-economic-affairs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_long_quote">Bolivians were never prevented by their government from buying burgers; they simply chose not to do so. This is not a victory over capitalism, it <em>is</em> capitalism.</blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.iea.org.uk/blog/mcdonald’s-withdrawal-from-bolivia-capitalism-in-action">iea.org.uk</a></div>
    <p></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Indian Inventor Disrupts The Period Industry | Co.Exist: World changing ideas and innovation]]></title>
    <link href="http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/19/an-indian-inventor-disrupts-the-period-industry-co-exist-world-changing-ideas-and-innovation/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://darron-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/12/19/an-indian-inventor-disrupts-the-period-industry-co-exist-world-changing-ideas-and-innovation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_bookmarklet_entry">
      <blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote">When Arunachalam Muruganantham hit a wall in his research on creating a sanitary napkin for poor women, he decided to do what most men typically wouldn’t dream of. He wore one himself&#8211;for a whole week. Fashioning his own menstruating uterus by filling a bladder with goat’s blood, Muruganantham went about his life while wearing women’s underwear, occasionally squeezing the contraption to test out his latest iteration. It resulted in endless derision and almost destroyed his family. But no one is laughing at him anymore, as the sanitary napkin-making machine he went on to create is transforming the lives of rural women across India.</blockquote>

<div class="posterous_quote_citation">via <a href="http://www.fastcoexist.com/1679008/an-indian-inventor-disrupts-the-period-industry">fastcoexist.com</a></div>
    <p>I love this story. Somebody sees a need, invents a ground breaking, low cost solution and has a way to live tens of thousands of people out of poverty. I hope that it catches on and he - and they - succeed.</p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
